Welcome to part 1 of the First Time Homebuyer Series and this series we're going to be going over how to buy your first home.
Buying your first home can be very stressful, but with the right preparation and guidance can be one of the most rewarding decisions of your life.
In this first episode we're going to be going over the fundamentals, how to choose the right area for you, how to make a budget, how to prepare financially, and lastly how to choose the best realtor for you.
When choosing the right area for you, you have to ask yourself what's important to you.
Do you care about the quality of the school? Do you need to be close to restaurants, stores, and parks? Do you need to be close to work or an MTA?
So it really depends on what's important to you.
When setting your realistic budget, you don't want your mortgage to be more than 33% of your income.
For example, if you make $10,000 a month, you don't want your mortgage payments to be more than $3,300 a month.
For getting prepared financially, you want to interview two or three mortgage brokers and have them compete against each other to see who can get you the most favorable rate.
When choosing your realtor, you should sit down with him, interview him, ask him if he knows about any first time home buyer programs and incentives to help you with your down payment or closing costs.
You should ask him if they have a trusted lender, attorney, and inspector that they use.
Ask them how they plan on negotiating on your behalf to get you the best deal.
And most importantly, just trust your instincts because you're going to be working closely with this realtor for the next 6 months to 12 months.
If you'd like a free home buyer guide, or you see a homeownership on the horizons for you in the next 6 months to 2 years,
DM me directly or call me at 917-951-2142